

Denver, CO

□ (402) 853-2785 | **☑** derek@homan.io | **☆** www.homan.io | **回** dhoman | **⊡** derek-homan

## Summary\_

Software developer with 5+ years of experience specializing in full stack development, web automation testing, and various other programming projects. The kind of nerd who loves Vim, prefers 2 space tabs over tabs (although doesn't mind other standards as long as everyone is consistent), and runs his own email server because he wanted to make his own email plugin. Interested in tackling new problems and learning unfamiliar technologies and tools whenever possible.

## Work Experience

### Vendavo (provides pricing optimization software)

Denver, CO

SENIOR .NET DEVELOPER

June 2018 - Present

- Ported and Redesigned an existing Silverlight project into React
- Modified, maintained, and expanded functionality of the backend code
- Technologies: React, Redux, C#

### CSG International (provides ordering, and CRM products for ISPs)

Omaha, NE

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER ENGINEER SENIOR

July 2016 - June 2018

- · Implemented unit and automated integration tests
- Provided estimates and implemented new features
- · Developed and tested bugfixes and back-ported them in Hotfixes and Patches
- Presented technical talks to coworkers, and provided feedback via Code Reviews
- Technologies: Angular, Redux

### idea5 (startup that aggregates data and generates reports for financial institutions)

Omaha, NE

FULL STACK SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

December 2013 - July 2016

- Improved slowest page load from 15-30 seconds to 2-3 seconds (by proposing and implementing a microservice) to generate thumbnails instead of live rendering
- · Discovered a security flaw of a t4 template exposing sensitive application details such as connection strings
- · Designed and implemented micro-services using Docker, Node.js, Elasticsearch, and Windows Azure
- Wrote the payment checkout system utilizing C# and Authorize.net
- Mentored an intern and presented several talks to fellow coworkers
- Technologies: Backbone Marionette, C# ASP.NET, Azure, Docker, Node.js

#### Nebraska Book Company (online web commerce bookstore)

Lincoln, NE

June 2012 - December 2013

.NET DEVELOPER

• Wrote, maintained and tested backend services used to manage orders and inventory

- Gathered requirements and developed specifications for projects involving multiple departments
- · Maintained, updated, and documented several legacy programs inherited from other programmers
- Technologies: C# and VB ASP.NET

### UCARE, University of Nebraska - Lincoln (embedded devices research group)

Lincoln, NE

May 2010 - May 2012

RESEARCH ASSISTANT

- Developed tracking devices (backpacks with sensors and GSMs) for Sandhill cranes as an undergraduate research assistant for Dr. Vuran
- · Performed field testing and gathered data
- Wrote drivers for various embedded devices
- Assembled and tested PCB sensor boards
- Technologies: C++, TinyOS

### Interact Incorporated (software development for ISPs and call centers)

Lincoln NF

INTERN

May 2009 - May 2010

- Found and fixed a critical issue blocking a project from release caused by bug in third party software (reverted the dependency)
- Designed and implemented flows for automated customer service portals using VXML (Voice XML)
- Worked on a project to automate generation of VXML applications with a GUI
- Technologies: bash, VXML, Java, C++

DEVELOPER January 2006 - December 2008

- · Front end design using Photoshop, CSS, and HTML
- Wrote scripts to automate testing web applications
- Developed, designed, and tested web applications
- Made an internal service to generate invoices for customers
- Technologies: C# ASP.NET, HTML, CSS

## Skills

**Programming** C, C++, C#, Java, LaTeX, Javascript

Web HTML, CSS, LESS, SASS, Angular, Backbone Marionette, React, Redux, Express

Platforms / Task Runners Azure, AWS, Docker, Serverless Framework, Ansible, Node.js, gulp.js

## Education

### University of Nebraska - Lincoln

Lincoln, NE

B.S. IN COMPUTER ENGINEERING

May 2012

• Got a Regents Scholarship which is given to promising students

# Presentations

**Nebraska Code** Lincoln, NE

PRESENTER FOR <A NEWB'S GUIDE TO GETTING STARTED WITH IONIC>

2015

· Guide on what the Ionic framework (hybird mobile app framework with Angular and Cordova) is and how to make a simple application with it

# Extracurricular Activity \_\_\_\_\_

**Omaha Coder Dojo** Omaha, NE

MENTOR • Helped 8-12 year olds learn how to code (advice, explainations, trouble shooting, etc) 2014

# Side Projects

#### **Personal Email Server**

• VPS server hosted on linode running dovecot, roundcube, and apache

### Dollar Game Picks (dollargamepicks.com)

Omaha, NE

CO-FOUNDER

2015-2016

- Failed startup where we provide predictions on whether or not to bet on the line for NFL games for a dollar and if we are wrong we give you a credit for another prediction
- · Wrote the website, Stripe integration, account management / registration, email automation (Sendgrid)
- Technologies: Sequelize, Node.js, Angular, Express

### Frigg.io

**FOUNDER** 2018-present

- · Wedding planning website using text messages to provide info and updates to attendees
- Technologies: Angular, Firebase, Twilio

# Hobbies/Miscellaneous\_\_\_\_\_

**Hobbies** Running, Hiking, Reading, Working on side projects

Favorite Books Lean Startup, The Pragmatic Programmer, The Design of Design, Getting Things Done, The Art of Happiness Personel Opinions / Favorites Git Rebases > Merges, Vim, Visual Studio Code, 2 space tabs (although project consistency trumps preference)

JULY 29, 2019 DEREK HOMAN · RÉSUMÉ